Okay, now we are in the final stages of this, and before we add in a crash detection, let's try to
get the scenery to move so our game can feel more immersive.
So what we want to happen is for this tree sprite to come down the side of the road as we start driving,
to make it feel like we are passing scenery.
And this code will be very similar to our code for our obstacle sprite.
So let's just copy it over and see what happens.
Moving over, we can just drag these blocks here.
And when you click play.
Well, yeah, I think that's to be expected.
Our trees just kind of act like cars.
And as silly as this is, with a few modifications, we can get this to work for us.
So obviously we don't want our trees in the middle of the road.
And we can fix this by taking out this block inside the go to block.
And here we can then add in a pick random.
And because we want it on the side of the road, we can have it pick a number between -250 and -200.
And I think we can also keep the size here the same as it looks.
All right.
Hitting play again.
Yeah.
Look at how much better that is.
The only thing now is that our trees are moving at a different speed to our road.
So if we move back to our road sprite, you can see we have the speed set to minus ten.
So let's do the same for our trees.
Hitting play again.
That's definitely better.
Although one small problem we have here is the trees are stacking up at the bottom of the screen, but
we can easily fix this by changing this.
If we check here to let's change it to let's say -200.
And also let's increase the spawning speed a bit by adjusting this pick random from 0.6 to 1.2, 0.62,
0.3.
And well that fixes that and our tree spawn more quickly.
Well good job.
But there's still a problem and I'm sure you can see.
Which is that we only have trees on the one side of the road.
And we could just duplicate the sprite, which would work.
But as you know, it's always good to keep your code dry.
As in don't repeat yourself.
So let's think of a smarter solution.
Right now, when our trees start as a clone, it goes to a random position between -250 and -200.
But we also want 202 50 as an option because this is the right side of the screen.
So first things first, let's duplicate this.
Pick random and then change its values to 202 50.
Okay, now that we've done that, how can we have it that sometimes it chooses this pick random while
other times it chooses this pick random.
Well, pause the video and try to see if you can figure this one out on your own.
Well, no, it's not as easy as you might think, but I bet you're up to it.
Okay, so as always, there are different ways we could get this to work.
But I'm going to show you how we can use variables to solve this.
So what we can do is create a variable called sides.
Then we can add this code block to the start of our.
When I start as a clone script.
Then make sure you change this to set sides input.
And after that bring in a pick random.
And here we will set it to be just 1 or 2.
Okay, now we can grab and if then conditional we can grab this equals to operator.
And finally the sides variable.
So.
What we want to do is have it like this.
If size equals one, then do whatever is in here.
Or if size is not one, which is two, then do whatever is in here.
So we can drag this go to block inside this first condition.
Then we can do is duplicate it and switch out this.
Pick random for this one here.
Then finally connect all these blocks together.
Well, let's run through this quickly.
When we start as a clone, we have a variable called sides, which we'll set to be either 1 or 2, which
indicates left or right.
Then if size equals one, the trees will spawn on the one side, and if size equals two, they'll spawn
the other side.
Okay, so hitting play.
Well, there you have it.
We have three spawning on both sides and it looks good.
I think we're almost there.
Just a bit of collision detection and our game will pretty much be done.